So you're Sparda's son?
So what if I am, Milkman?
The answer is obvious.
I'll take your soul.
Hey, if you're going to help me out,
could you do it a little more quietly?
Help you? Don't get the wrong idea, pal.
I just targeted a demon, that's all.
A white demon.
You did! You definitely promised me!
Like hell I did.
Yes you did! You said
you'd take me to the ocean.
What the hell would you
want to do at the ocean?
Play, obviously! Go swimming, get
sunburned, eat good food, that stuff.
You can do that stuff anywhere.
Doing it at the ocean is
what gives it meaning!
Okay, fine.
Really?!
I'll lend you the car, so go by yourself.
Yeah, right! If I could drive
myself, there's no way I'd ask you...
What?! I dare you to say that again!
Please don't misunderstand me. I just...
Shut up! Get out of here!
Thanks for waiting!
What's going on with them?
Oh, that guy said the boss's
strawberry sundaes weren't good.
Strawberry sundaes...
You mean these?
If I offended you, I apologize.
I only meant to say that using
slightly less sugar would make them--
You bastard! You're still saying that?!
I don't even want your
money now! Hurry up and--
Hold on, Fredi.
I've got something of an
attachment to the sundaes here myself.
But they seem to be sweeter than usual today.
That man is right.
He got all sulky...
Apparently he's a sensitive guy
behind that gruff face of his.
It seems I've hurt his feelings.
Devil!
Please, someone help me! Sh-She's a devil!
Yep, I'm a devil. And what about you?
That's right...
I'm a devil, too!
Are you still alive?
I've got a question for you.
Do you know about the white devil
that's been showing up around here lately?
Nope. Even if I did, I
wouldn't tell you who...
That's a lie! I was lying!
I totally know who he is.
The guy they call Sparda's apprentice.
Apprentice?
Yes, that's right.
He's apparently extremely tough,
and the rumor is that when
he takes a sword in his hand,
one or two thousand demons
get killed in a split second!
Um, are we through yet, Miss? Can I...
...eat you now?
Anyway, I heard rumors like that around town.
I see. So you called me here to
pass the word on to me, is that it?
That's right.
How unusually kind of you.
I just thought I'd give you a little warning.
It'd be a pity if I ended up
killing him instead of you, right?
Since it kinda seems like
there's history between you two.
Maybe so.
Sorry, but he asked for me by name.
I won't let anyone interfere.
A demon who fought to
protect the human world...
My mentor... Sparda, the dark knight.
It's been 2,000 years since that battle.
And now the one who has
appeared before us is not you,
but your son Dante.
Did I startle you?
Yeah.
Liar.
Why do you say that?
Because you're not startled at all!
Sheesh, I can't tell if you're kind
or cold. You're the opposite of Dante.
Opposite?
Yep. Because I can't tell
if Dante is cold or kind.
So in the end, you can't tell, huh?
Oh, I do know one thing!
You both love strawberry sundaes
even though you're grown-ups.
What are you doing?
People-watching, perhaps.
You sure seem to have time on your hands.
It's pretty peaceful, huh?
Yes...
It really is peaceful.
I'd like to have times like these forever.
Ah, Lord Modeus always seems so placid.
I can hardly believe that
the two of you are twins.
But really, what a waste. I wonder why
Lord Modeus abandoned swordsmanship?
I'm told that long ago, his skill
with his sword was great enough
to make the whole demon world tremble.
Well, I suppose he felt he could never hope
to beat you, Lord Baul, and so he gave up.
Sparda entrusted his true
strength and will to Modeus, not to me.
L-L-Lord Baul, I can't breathe...
Ouch...
What would the likes of you
know about my brother and I?
Oh, I know what you have in mind.
You intend to go there, don't you?
To the Devil May Cry.
Throw it back this way!
Hey, wait!
And get this! Dante eats
nothing but pizza every day!
What do you think of an
adult who acts like that?
Well, it's not for me.
If I were going to date someone,
no way would it be a guy like that!
He's lucky if he gets one job a week.
Oh, Dante runs an odd-job
business called the "Devil May Cry."
But no matter how many jobs Morrison brings,
he just screws them all up,
and it's a real problem!
And it seems like he owes Lady a lot of
money, too. Honestly, Dante is just so...
Oh no! I'm on dinner duty today!
If I don't get back quick, the head
of the orphanage will yell at me.
Well, I'm off!
Hey!
Will you be at loose ends tomorrow too?
You will, right? I'll make
you a strawberry sundae, then!
Come to the Devil May Cry tomorrow!
That's a promise!
Huh, a strawberry sundae, eh?
What a cute little girl.
Yes.
No doubt that girl would grieve too...
...if Dante were to end up dead.
"Closed until further notice"?
Heh, did he go off to train
in the mountains or something?
Dante isn't here.
I see.
Why? Your opponent is Sparda, isn't he?
So why would you fight Dante?
Sparda is dead.
He's alive! I'm sure that
somewhere out there he's...
Did you find it, then? Proof that he's alive?
Well...
I waited 2,000 years.
But Sparda did not appear!
And so you're going after
Sparda's son, Dante?
That's right. If I get his soul, I'll
also get the dark knight Sparda's power.
So you insist on this?
Yes.
Then there's no help for it. In that case...
If you insist on this, then please
do it after you've defeated me.
I have no desire to battle someone
who abandoned the way of the sword.
When he gets back, tell him to come to me.
I see... A duel with me, eh?
Please run.
My brother should not fight you. And you...
What could you have to gain by fighting him?
Even if I don't have anything
to gain, he does, doesn't he?
Because word is that if he
gets my soul or whatever,
he'll get the same powers as my old man.
I don't know who spread that rumor,
but in the end, your brother's
another one who wants to capture it
and become king of the demon
world or something, am I right?
You don't understand
anything about my brother.
He just wants to fight someone strong.
He has no thought of
ruling the demon world...
What about you?
In truth, aren't you itching
even more than your brother is?
Itching for my soul.
You're going to him, Dante?
When someone picks a fight
with me, I give it to them.
That's the only reason I fight.
I came, Milkman.
Let's settle this thing
fast, before I catch a cold.
What's wrong? Too scared to do anything
if your little brother isn't with you?
Heh, well this makes me happy.
I've always wanted to know what a
swordsman trained by my father would be like.
Looks like my father's
swordsmanship isn't that great.
I need you to give me
some more amusement here!
What's wrong? Done already?
I-I must not...
...lose here...
For the sake of Modeus as well,
Modeus who gave up the sword for me...
I must not...
be defeated here!
So you'll finally show your true nature, eh?
Brother...
I will surpass the dark knight Sparda!
Two thousand years ago, when the
demon and human worlds were connected,
Sparda, my brother, and I made a promise.
We promised we'd each live true to
our aspirations and carry them out.
Soon afterwards, Sparda came to this
land all alone, to protect the human world.
And my brother never
aligned himself with either world,
merely waiting devotedly
for Sparda to return.
Yes... Dueling with Sparda, the
best swordsman in the demon realm,
was his only reason for living.
I abandoned my sword.
It had begun to disgust me.
It created nothing, and could even
rob my brother of his reason to live.
And so since I killed your brother,
who was your reason to live...
...now your reason to live is
to take revenge against me?
You brothers couldn't be
any more old-fashioned.
Morning, Dante!
Honestly! That Dante...
Wake up, Dante! Come on!
Shut up. What the heck do you want?
Today I'm making a special strawberry
sundae for that man in the black coat.
Sheesh, no matter how much I clean
this place, you mess it right up again!
I don't think he'll come.
Why not?
--A promise...
--Promise?
Yeah.
He said he'd remembered an old
promise he made a long time ago.
It's all going according to plan.
This is what I want.
Now there's only one more thing left.
You hear news about parents
abusing their children all the time,
but I still think I want to keep believing that
parents love their children unconditionally.
My mother died protecting me.
Maybe that's why...
I apparently have some humanity in me, too.
And maybe Patty's mother abandoned Patty
because circumstances
made it unavoidable.